よし　お前ら３人は 俺様が責任を持って
Okay! I'll take responsibility for bringing
審査会場　最寄りの港まで 連れて行ってやらぁ。
you three to the port closest to the exam site.
い…　やった！
Yay!
船長に気に入られた ゴン　クラピカ　レオリオの３人は
After winning the captain's favor, the trio of Gon, Kurapika, and Leorio
ここ　ドーレ港に到着していた
arrived safely at Dolle Harbor.
ありがとう　船長　楽しかったよ！
Thanks, Captain! I had a great time!
アハハ…　わしも なかなか楽しませてもらったぞ。
I had fun, too.
そうだ そのお礼といっちゃ何だが １つ　アドバイスをくれてやろう。
Right! As a token of my appreciation, I'll give you some advice.
アドバイス？ ほれ　あの山のてっぺんに 大きな杉の木が見えるだろう。 うん。
Advice? Look. See that big cedar tree on the hilltop? Uh-huh. You should make your way there first.
近道？　分かった！ あの杉の木だね。
A shortcut? Got it! So, I just need to head for that tree!
行ってみるよ　船長！　ありがとう。
I'll do that, Captain! Thanks!
達者でな。
Best of luck!
うん　船長も　元気でね！
Yep! Same to you! Take care!
安心しな　ジン
Rest easy, Ging.
お前の息子は いい子に育ってる
Your son has grown into a respectable young man.
うん　そりゃおかしいぜ。 何で？
Huh... That's strange. Why?
だってよ 送られて来た通知書には 試験会場は　ザバン地区の どこかって書かれてるぜ。
According to the notice I received, the exam is supposedly being held
somewhere in Zaban City.
今　ここだろ？
Right now, we're here.
あの杉の木は　ザバン地区とは 反対の方角じゃねえか。
That tree is in the opposite direction.
聞き間違いではないのか？ ううん。
Perhaps you misheard him?
確かに あの杉の木って　いってたよ。
No, he told me to head toward that cedar tree.
そうか…。
I see...
大体　この通知書も悪いよな。
And this notice isn't any help!
ザバン地区の　どこかってだけじゃ 分かんねえっつうの。
Where, exactly, in Zaban City
are we meant to go?
わずかな情報を頼りに 会場へ　たどり着く
Our task is to find the exam site,
using a limited amount of information.
それも　ハンター試験を受ける 条件の１つなのさ。
Just another test before we'll be allowed
to take the Hunter Exam.
もちろん　分かってるさ！ そんなことはよ！
I-I knew that... I already knew that!
とりあえず　俺　行ってみる きっと何か　訳があるんだよ。
Anyway, I'll go have a look. The captain must have had
a reason to suggest that.
おいおい　本気かよ？
Hey, hey... You're serious?
ザバン行きのバスが出てんだぞ あれに乗りゃあ　いいじゃねえか。
The bus to Zaban is about to leave. We should just take it.
おい！
Hey!
…ったく　あいつは　もう少し
Man...
ひとを疑うことを 覚えたほうがいいな。
He's gotta learn that you
can't trust everyone.
え？　おい　クラピカ！
Huh? Hey! Kurapika!
船長の言葉というよりも ゴンの行動に興味があるね。
Gon's behavior interests me more
than the captain's advice.
しばらく　彼に付き合ってみるさ。
I'm going with him.
あぁ　そうかよ　じゃあな！ 短い付き合いだったが　元気でな。
Oh, is that so? See ya. Wasn't very long... Nice knowing you.
ケッ　意外に主体性のねえ奴だな。
Guess he's not as independent as I'd thought...
俺は　手っ取り早く　バスで行くぜ。
I'm just gonna take the bus!
やはり　罠だったか。
So it was a trap...
バスは　一台も ザバン地区に着いてないらしい。
Seems none of the buses have
made it to Zaban City.
フフっ ルーキーは　バカ正直だから 大概　ここで脱落するな ヘッヘッヘッ…。
Rookies usually fail this part
because they're too naïve.
待て　待て　待て！ 待ってくれよ！
Wait, wait, wait! Wait for me!
ほら　お前らだけじゃ 寂しいだろ？
Well, I knew you guys would
be lonely without me.
俺も１人じゃ　つまんねえしさぁ。
And it's no fun traveling alone.
まっ　もう　しばらく 付き合ってやろうかなぁって。 ハハハ…。
So I decided to stick with you
guys a while longer.
薄気味悪い所だなぁ 人っ子一人　見当たらねえぜ。
This is a creepy place... I don't see a single person.
ううん　結構いるよ。 なっ　何？
No, there are plenty here. What?
な…　何だ？　こいつら。
Wh-What's with the freak show?
ドキドキ…。
Exciting...
ドキドキ？
E-Exciting?
ドキドキ…。
Exciting...
ドキドキ。
Exciting.
ドキドキ　２択クイズ！
Exciting two-choice quiz!
お前達　あの　一本杉を 目指しているんだろう？
You boys are headed for that
tree on the hill, correct?
この町を抜けて行くしか 道は　ないぞ。
To reach that tree, you must pass through this town. Huh?
これから クイズを　一問だけ出題する。
I shall administer a single-question quiz.
おいおい 何なんだよ　いきなり。
H-Hold on! What's going on here?
考える時間は５秒間。
You'll have five seconds to state your answer.
間違えたら　即　失格。
Give the wrong answer, and you're disqualified.
今年のハンター試験は諦めな。
You'll have to give up on taking
this year's Hunter Exam.
なるほど　これもハンター試験の 関門の１つというわけか。
I see... Then this is part of the Hunter Exam.
そういうことか クイズなら得意だぜ。
I see how it is. I happen to be a quiz expert.
…って　一問!?
Wait. Only one question?
答えは　１か２で答えること。
Your answer will be either the number 1 or 2.
それ以外の　曖昧な答えは 全て間違いと見なす。
Any other answer will be considered incorrect.
ちょっと待てよ この３人で　一問なのか？
Hold on! All three of us share one question?
もし　こいつが間違えたら 俺まで失格ってことかよ。
So if one of them answers incorrectly,
I'm disqualified, too?
あり得ないね。
As if that would happen!
むしろ　逆の可能性が高くて 泣きたくなるよ。
What scares me is the high likelihood
of the vice versa happening.
何だと？　この！
What was that?
でもさ　３人のうち誰かが 答えを知ってればいいんだから
But you know... This way's easier, since only one of us
needs to know the answer.
楽じゃない？　俺　クイズ苦手だし。
I'm not good at quizzes.
まぁ…。 確かに。
I suppose... Fair point.
おいおい
Hey, there. Hurry it up.
早くしてくれよ 何なら　俺が先に答えるぜ。
Or else I'll answer the question first.
誰だ　お前。
Who are you?
港から　ずっと俺達の後ろを ついて来てた人だよ。
He followed us here, all the way from port.
えっ　マジか？
Huh? Seriously?
悪ぃな　坊ず　お前達の話を 偶然　聞いちまったのさぁ。
Sorry, kid. I happened to overhear your conversation.
どうするかね？
What will you do?
本人が　ああいってんだし ここは譲ろうぜ。
He seems eager to take it. We should let him go first.
問題の傾向も分かるしよ。
That way, we'll know what kind
of question to expect.
俺は別にいいよ。 特に異論はない。
I don't mind. I have no objection.
じゃ　お先に。
Then I'll get to it.
バカ　先に行って　お前らに たっぷり 罠を仕掛けてやるんだよ
Fools. I'll leave a trail of traps behind me.
それでは　問題。
Here is your question...
お前の母親と恋人が悪党に捕まり 一人しか助けられない。
Evil villains have captured your mother and lover. You can only save one.
１母親　２恋人。
Select 1 for your mother, or 2 for your lover.
お前は　どちらを助ける？
Which will you save?
え？ 何だよ　そのクイズ。
H-How is this even a quiz?
[外:8A7B963437C50F361623A5DFC5E0B8D2]ピンポン 答えは　１だ！
The answer is 1.
ほう　なぜ　そう思う？
Oh? Why do you say that?
そりゃあ 母親は　代えが利かないからな。
Because you can't replace your mother.
恋人は また　別のを見つけりゃいい。
But you can find another lover.
何!?
What?
通りな。
You may pass.
フッ。 何だと!?
What?
こういうのは　ばあさんの好みに 合わせときゃ　正解なのさ。
You just have to tell the old lady
what she wants to hear.
あばよ！
Adios.
おいおい！　ふざけんじゃねえ あんなの正解なわけねえだろ！
Hey, now! That's all bull! How was that the right answer?
ばあさんが気に入る答えを いやぁ　いいってのか!?
We're supposed to give the answer
the old lady wants?
それが正しいってのかよ！
And that's considered correct?
おい　何とか　いえよ！
Hey, say something!
ケッ　こんな茶番 付き合ってられるか！
I won't put up with this sham.
俺は別の道を探すぜ！ もう　遅い。
I'll find a different route. It's too late.
ここで　クイズに答えなければ お前は　即　失格だ。
Refuse to take the quiz, and you're disqualified.
くっ…　ふざけんな！
Th-That's just ridiculous!
あんな問題 人によって答えが違うし
Different people would expect different answers!
正解なんて言葉で　くくれる もんじゃねえだろうがよ！
There is no right answer!
「言葉では　くくれない」。
No right answer...
そうか！
I see!
ん？ レオリオ！
Leorio!
待ちな！ うっ。
Wait!
猫目の坊やは 気づいたようだね
The cat-eyed boy has figured it out.
これ以上のおしゃべりは 許さないよ。
Not another word from you.
余計な発言をしたら　即　失格だ。
Say anything but the answer, and you're immediately disqualified.
気づけ　レオリオ これは簡単なトリックだ
Wake up, Leorio... It's a simple trick...
ゴン…
Gon...
それでは　問題。
Here is your question...
お前の息子と娘が誘拐されて どちらか　一人しか取り戻せない。
Your son and daughter have been kidnapped. You can only rescue one.
１息子　２娘。
Select 1 for your son, or 2 for your daughter.
お前は　どちらを取り戻す？
Which will you rescue?
ナメやがって！
She's making fun of us...
５。
Five.
４。 いい気になって 秒読みしやがれ
Go ahead and count down, you hag. Four.
Three.
Two.
１…。
One.
ブ　終了。
Buzz. Time's up.
止めるな　クラピカ！
Don't stop me, Kurapika!
俺は　こいつに説教してやんねえと 気が治まらねえ！
I won't be satisfied until I've
taught this hag a lesson!
落ち着け　レオリオ！ これが落ち着いていられるか！
Calm down, Leorio! How am I supposed to calm down?
せっかくの合格を棒に振る気か!?
You'll waste our correct response.
へ？　合格？
Correct response?
我々は正解したんだよ。
We gave the right answer.
「沈黙」　それが正しい答えなんだ。
Silence was the correct response.
「沈黙」？　何だって？
Silence? What do you mean...
いみじくも さっき　君が言った通りだ。
You hit the nail on the head.
((正解なんて言葉で　くくれる もんじゃねえだろうがよ！))
There is no right answer!
そう　このクイズに正解などない。
Precisely. This quiz had no right answer.
しかし　答えは　１と２でしか いえないルールだ。
However, we could only state
1 or 2 as the answer.
つまり　答えられない 「沈黙」しかないんだ。
In other words, we weren't meant
to respond at all. Silence was the only response.
しかし　さっきの野郎は…。 「正解」とは　いっていない。
But what about that other guy?
「通れ」といっただけだ。
They never said he gave the right answer.
She only said, "You may pass."
つまり　こっちの道は 正しい道ではない。
In other words, this path is the wrong path.
そうだろ？
Am I right?
その通り。
Precisely.
正しい道は　こっちだよ。
The correct path is over here.
一本道だ ２時間も歩けば頂上に着く。
This leads directly to the tree. Walk two hours, and you'll reach the top.
何だ　そういうことだったのか。
Oh, so that's what this was about...
その　一本杉の下の 山小屋に住む夫婦は
A couple lives in the cabin beneath that tree.
ナビゲーターをやっている。
They serve as Navigators.
彼らの眼鏡にかなえば 会場まで案内してくれるだろう。
If you meet their standards, I believe that
they will guide you to the exam site.
ばあさん　悪かった 手荒なまねをして。
Gran, I'm sorry for my rudeness.
なに　構わんよ。
Don't be. I don't mind.
お前みたいな奴に会いたくて やってる仕事さ。
I do this job because I enjoy
meeting people like you.
え？
Huh?
頑張って　いいハンターになりな。
Do your best to become a good Hunter.
ダメだ どうしても　答え　出ないや。
It's no use. I can't think of an answer.
ハハハ…　お前　まだ 答えを考えてたのかよ。
You were still trying to find an answer?
もう　いいんだぜ。 え？　何で？
You can stop. Huh? Why?
クイズは　もう終わったんだ。 それは分かってるよ　でも
The quiz is over. I know. But...
でもさ もし　本当に大切な２人のうち
But you know... What if I run into a situation like that
どっちか　１人しか 助けられない時が来たら
and I can only save one person...
どうする？
What should I do then?
どちらを選んでも 正解じゃないけど
It wouldn't be right to choose just one...
どちらか 必ず選ばなきゃならない時が いつか　来るかもしれないんだ。
But one day, I might have
to make that choice.
そうじゃ　それが
That's right.
このクイズを出した　本当の意味
That is the true purpose of this test.
あらゆる残酷な空想に 耐えておけ
You must be prepared to face the
worst possible scenarios...
現実は突然 無慈悲になるものだからな
Because harsh reality strikes without warning.
いつか来る　別れ道に備えて
You must be prepared for
the day your paths diverge.
歩いて２時間だぁ？
"Walk two hours," she said?
２時間なんて　２時間前に 過ぎちまったぞ！　くっそ。
It was two hours, two hours ago! Damn.
こんなんで ホントに　会場に着けんのか？
Another "Beware of Magical Beasts" sign? Are we ever gonna make it to the exam site?
お腹すいたよ！
I'm hungry!
ウンコしたいよ…。 レオリオ　置いてくよ！
I need to take a dump! Leorio! We'll leave you behind!
あっ　見えたぞ！ おい！
I've gotta take a leak, too! I see it. Hey!
留守かな？
Hello? Anyone home? Are they out?
入るぜ？
We're coming in.
魔獣だ！ 魔獣!?
It's a Magical Beast! A Magical Beast?
変幻魔獣キリコ！ 人に化けることもできる。
A Transforming Magical Beast, the Kiriko! They can take human form!
高い知能を持った獣だ！
That's an extremely intelligent creature!
女の人が！
There's a woman in his arms!
倒れてる奴も 早く手当てしないと！
And the guy on the floor
needs medical attention...
妻を…
P-Please...
妻を助けてくれ…。
Please save my wife...
レオリオ！　ケガ人を頼む！
Leorio, we'll leave the injured man to you!
任せろ！
Got it!
この深くて暗い森の中 あの　かすかな影を 捉えて離さぬとは
He can follow that faint shadow,
even through this dark forest.
フッ　大した奴だ
Impressive.
キリコ！　その人を放せ！
Kiriko! Let her go!
腕ずくで　取り返してみな！
Take her from me, if you can!
すごいや！ あいつ　しゃべったよ！
Wow! He can talk!
魔獣キリコは 人の言葉も操れるんだ。
That Magical Beast,
the Kiriko, uses human speech.
へぇ！　言葉が通じるなら早いや！
Oh. That makes this a lot easier!
やい！　うすのろキリコ！
Hey! Silly Kiriko!
何!?
What?
は…　速い！
H-He's fast!
クラピカ！
Kurapika!
はぁ…　ムチャする奴め。
He's so reckless...
ギィ…　このガキ！　覚えてろよ！
Stupid kid. You'll pay for this!
待て！
Wait!
大丈夫か？ どこか　ひどく痛む所は　あるか？
Are you okay? Are you injured anywhere?
大丈夫 それより　夫は？　どうなったの？
I'm okay. What about my husband? How is he?
心配ない　我々の仲間が見ている。
Don't worry. Our friend is taking care of him.
お願い　夫の所へ連れて行って…。
Please take me to my husband!
あっ　この入れ墨…。
Those tattoos...
君は…。 クラピカ！
You're... Kurapika!
無事か？ レオリオ？
You okay? Leorio?
よかった　無事だったんだな。
Whew... Guess you guys are all right.
男の容体は　どうだ？
How is that man?
ああ　心配なさそうだ 見た目ほど　傷は深くなかった。
Yeah, no worries. The wound wasn't as deep as it looked.
今は　鎮痛剤をのんで 家で　ぐっすり寝てるよ。
I gave him some painkillers,
and he's sound asleep in the cabin.
そうか。
I see...
ウッフフ…　なぜ分かった？
How did you know?
なぜ　俺が偽者だと分かったのだ？
How did you know I was an impostor?
別に偽者だと思ったわけではない。
I didn't think that you were.
私は　「ケガ人を頼む」といい レオリオは　「任せろ」といった。
I told Leorio to take care of the
injured man, and he consented.
再び魔獣が 襲って来ないとも限らないのに そのケガ人を置き去りにして のこのこ やって来るような奴だから殴った。
Given the Magical Beast is still on the loose, I attacked you for foolishly leaving
an injured man on his own.
それだけだ。 フフフ…！
That's all.
さて　１つ答えてくれ。
Now I need you to answer my question.
お前は　一体　何者だ？ フッ。
Who are you?
待て！
Wait!
ガキのくせに　素早い奴だ。
For a kid, you're pretty quick.
この俺様に 一撃を食らわすとはな。
Didn't expect you'd land a blow on me.
教えてやるよ　その代償が
You're about to discover
恐ろしく 高くついたってことをな！ キリキリ　キリキリ…。
the high price that accomplishment came with!
君　誰？ ゲッ。
Who are you?
俺が　さっき殴ったのは 君じゃ　ないよね？
You aren't the one I hit.
さっきの奴の友達なの？
Are you his friend?
何で　俺が さっきの奴とは別だと分かった？
How can you tell that I'm not the same one?
えっ？　だって 顔が　全然　違うじゃん。
Huh? Your face is completely different.
声だって　君のほうが 少し高くて　細い感じだし。 クックック…　フハハ…！
And your voice is a little higher and thinner.
何？ 俺　何か　おかしいこと　いった？
What? Did I say something funny?
面白いもんが見られるよ！
Come out here! You're gonna love this!
ふむ。
Hmm...
何年ぶりだろうねぇ ウチら夫婦を見分けた人間は。
How many years has it been since someone
was able to tell us apart?
嬉しいねぇ。
I'm ecstatic!
声と顔の違い　分かるか？ いや　全く。
Can you tell their faces and
voices are different? No, not at all...
あのね　俺とクラピカに殴られたほうが 旦那さんなんだって。
You see, the one Kurapika and I
beat up is the husband.
我々は　ナビゲーター。
We are the Navigators.
家族で　ハンター試験の サポートをしている。
Our family provides support
for the Hunter Exam.
娘です。 息子です。
I'm their daughter! I'm their son!
…ったく　すっかり だまされちまったぜ。
Man, you had us fooled.
ハンター試験の会場は 毎年　変わる。
The Hunter Exam changes site every year.
その場所を自力で探すのは 非常に困難だ。
It's quite difficult to locate it.
そこで　我々　ナビゲーターが 受験者達を そこまで案内しているのだ。
So we Navigators help by guiding
the applicants to the site.
へぇ　そうだったんだ。
Oh, that's how it works.
でも　受験者全員を 案内するわけじゃ　ないよ。
But we don't help every candidate.
ハンター試験を受けるに ふさわしい人間かどうか
We test applicants to see if they're qualified
我々が試して　選別しているんだ。
to take the exam.
クラピカ殿。 はい。
Kurapika-dono. Yes.
あなたは わずかなヒントを見逃さず
You successfully used the most vague of hints
見事　私達２人が 夫婦でないことを見破りました。
to determine that we weren't spouses.
このヒントとなる入れ墨は この地方に住む女性が　生涯 独身を通す証しとして彫るもの。
The hint was these tattoos
which, in this region, mark a woman as single for life.
クラピカ殿の博学さが 証明されたわけです。
Kurapika-dono demonstrated that
he is very knowledgeable.
よって　合格とします。
Therefore, he passes.
やったね　クラピカ。 ああ。
Way to go, Kurapika. Thanks.
レオリオ殿。 ああ。
Leorio-dono. Yeah...
あなたは　結局　最後まで 私の正体に気づかなかった。 ギクっ。
You never realized my true identity.
しかし　傷の処置は 医者以上に早くて的確。
However, you dressed my injuries faster and more thoroughly than any doctor.
そして　何より 妻の身を案じるふりをしていた 私に対し
Most importantly, you continued
to reassure me
ずっと　力強い励ましの言葉を かけ続けてくれた。
that my wife was safe.
よしてくれ　恥ずかしい…。
S-Stop it... It's embarrassing...
その心の温かさは ハンター試験を受験するに値する。
Your kindness makes you worthy
to take the Hunter Exam.
よって　合格だ。
Thus, you pass.
ホ…　ホントか！　はぁ。
R-Really?
よかった。 やったね！
Thank goodness... You did it!
そして最後に　ゴン殿。 はい！
And finally, Gon-dono. Yes!
お前の　その　とてつもなく 人間離れした運動能力　観察力
Your superhuman physical ability
and powers of observation
ハンター試験を受けるに 十分　値する。
make you worthy to take the Hunter Exam.
合格だ。
You pass.
さぁ　君達を ハンター試験会場まで案内しよう！
We will now take you to the exam site.
よかったね ３人一緒に合格できて。
Isn't it great that we all passed?
喜ぶのは　早い。
It's too early to celebrate.
あくまで 受験資格を手にしただけだ。
We've merely earned the right
to take the real exam.
いいじゃねえか　前進したことに 変わりは　ねえだろ！
What's wrong with celebrating a little? We're making progress.
まったく　能天気な奴らだ。
Honestly, you people really should think.
てめぇ　いちいち生意気…　うわ！
Hey! Why must you be such a smart-ass?
暴れるんじゃ　ねえ！ 落ちても知らないよ！
Stop moving around!
アッハッハ…！
If you fall, blame yourself!
つかの間の空中遊泳を楽しむ ゴン達　一行
Gon and his friends enjoy a brief
journey through the sky.
しかし　彼らは　まだ スタートラインにすら 着いていなかった
However, they still haven't reached
the starting line.